

ARNI STEINGRIMSSON

Director of Data Sciences & Artificial Intelligence

- @ arnis.us@gmail.com
- **J** 970-439-1667
- Ormond Beach, FL USA

- in arnisteingrimsson
- arnisteingrimsson
- M arnis.us

INTERESTS

Cross Country Skiing (Hiking

Outdoor Activities

Computers | Airplanes

LEADERSHIP

Leader Attentive

Communicative | Positive

Trustworthy Creative

Responsible | Motivative

SKILLS

Big Data

Spark Databricks SQL

Vaex | Dask

ML

Scikit-Learn Orange

SAS

DL Frameworks

Torch Tensorflow CNTK

Computer Vision

OpenCV) Detectron

NLP

NLTK Stanford Core NLP
spaCy LightTag

Annotation Tools

MSFT VoTT LabelBox

ABOUT ME

An executive with more than 8 years of experience in Data Science, Machine Learning, and Artificial Intelligence and over 12 years of engineering experience. Responsible for Analytic's revenue growth, team structure, technical requirements, processes, and execution. Responsible for building out Data Science and AI service offerings that serve clients in Banking, Healthcare, Financial Services, Energy, and Retail.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Data Sciences & Artificial Intelligence | AgileThought

June 2017 - Current

▼ Tampa,FL

Objectives and Responsibilities of the Director of Data Science Leadership/Supervisory Role: The primary role of the Director of Data Science and AI is heading the data science and AI activities in at AgileThought. In this position, the Director of Data Science and AI is responsible for developing the team's culture, hiring standards, and delivery policies. He develops the data science and AI vision and oversees its adoption among AgileThinker in the data science and AI unit.

The Director of Data Science and AI oversees the data science and AI unit's training and competency development, determining best practices and work standards. The Director of Data Science and AI initiates data science programs across the unit not only with a view of improving the unit's performance but also with a focus on revenue growth and achievement of the business' overall targets and objectives.

The Director of Data Science and AI additionally leads the unit in the development of new insights, advanced modeling techniques, and data science capabilities. In his leadership capacity, the Director of Data Science and AI is also responsible for the preparation of white papers, conference presentations, and scientific publications.

The Director of Data Science and AI personally works on challenging fundamental data science an AI issues where necessary, realizes, and develops solutions independently. The Director of Data Science and AI is ultimately accountable for the project portfolio within the data science and AI unit.

In this capacity, the Director of Data Science and AI is also plays a mentorship role where he encourages the professional growth of key data science personnel, assisting in the execution of their duties upon request, and readying them for the assumption of his functions in his retirement or absence.

Strategy: The Director of Data Science and AI also plays a strategic role and in this position he is tasked with building and managing new data tables that support data collection in the department, cross-channel data integration, data visualization, dashboards, causality modeling, predictive analytics, prescriptive analytics, and data mining.

In this position, the Director of Data Science and AI establishes actionable KPIs and success metrics and ensures that there is timely and accurate reporting. In his strategic role, the Director of Data Science and AI leverages data science tools and techniques in analyzing large data-sets that will enable him to develop custom models and algorithms to

COCO Annotator

RL Frameworks

RLLib Horizon ReAgent

Evolutionary Computing

DEAP

Simulators

Anylogic MESA SimPy

GIS

QGIS GeoPandas Folium ipyleaflet

HPC

Oracle Grid Engine

Microsoft HPC Ray

Programming Languages

Python C/C++ C#

JAVA FORTRAN PEARL

MATLAB latex OpenCL

CUDA NXOpen R

CAD

NX CATIA ProE
AutoCAD

FEA

NX Nastran

ANSYS Mechanical

Composite

FiberSIM)

NX Laminate Composite

Meshers

ANSYS Mesher ANSYS ICEM
GridPro PointWise

NX Mesher AcuSim Mesher

GridGen

CFD

ANSYS Fluent ANSYS CFX

NX Advanced Flow AcuSim

uncover insights, trends, and patterns in the data, which will be useful in availing informed courses of action.

In this capacity, the Director of Data Science and AI will create data science and AI platforms to test and experiment with techniques inclusive of advanced analytics, behavioral modeling, and churn capitalizing on new data science approaches that can yield revenue for the business.

Collaboration: The role of the Director of Data Science and AI is also a collaborative one and in this position, the Director of Data Science and AI partners with senior business executives and key stakeholders in creating the data science roadmap tailored to constantly aid AI governance across the client engagements and improve the overall business performance.

The Director of Data Science and AI partners with other non-technical units within the business assisting them in understanding how data science can benefit them and improve their effectiveness and performance. The Director of Data Science and AI works closely with sales and marketing resources for the purpose of facilitating the development and sales of services and solutions.

Knowledge: The Director of Data Science and AI takes initiative and stays up to date with the latest data science and AI trends, techniques, and best practices, determining how to incorporate the most suitable practices in the department.

Research Scientist | Biodesix

April 2014 - May 2017

Steamboat Spring, CO

A cancer research company based out of Boulder, Colorado. Biodesix was 2015 fastestgrowing private company according to Denver Business Journal. Developed molecular diagnostic tests that could help the patients find the treatment that works for them, personalized medicine. Tests based on serum/plasma samples acquired on Deep MALDI TOF mass spectrometer. The core of the classification tool is a deep learning network that is designed for tests based on deep data. The network is designed to be generalizable and optimized. Speech and pattern recognition algorithms are used in the network to recognize proteins instead of words. The network is mostly supervised learning but sometimes semi-supervised. Multiple levels of abstraction/representation are learned by machine learning algorithms that were inspired by brains. This can be viewed as meta-learning. Responsible for the HPC system for the company as well as managed many R&D projects. HPC system administrator tasks included the installation of hardware as well as software monitoring, logging, and permission. Other tasks include but are not limited to statistical analysis such as regression-, correlation-, multivariate- and survival analysis, ranking, clustering, and visualization. Prototyped algorithms are written in MATLAB and C/C++. Cancer research classifier development has many difficulties. Problems such as few samples and many features occur daily and there is a high risk of over-fitting. Great tools, a deep understanding of the deep learning algorithm, and the experience was a recipe for successful test delivery.

Aerospace Engineer | Siemens Energy, Wind R&D

ä January 2011 – April 2014

Boulder, CO

Developed and started up professional software competency within the group. Established a personal and team software process that included Jira for scrum project planning and tracking. Mercurial and Git for code repository and Doxygen, Doxygraph, and Graphviz for documentation. Responsible for all blade surfaces and geometries of new and concept wind turbine blades. Blade surfaces that get handed over to manufacturing. Oversaw all CAD automation that uses CAD's core C/C++ API. Developed code on Windows and Linux even though the CAD did not support automation on LINUX. One of the applications was a core tool for blade development and production. It automatically generates blade surface models in the CAD. Which can be sent to manufacturing or to the Aero team for Computational Fluid Dynamics analysis (CFD). The tool is still being used today. The tool has made a tremendous impact and enhanced repeatability and reduced cycle time by days and weeks. Responsible for performance testing of multiple components of a wind turbine blade, components such as airfoil sections, winglets, and vortex

OpenFoam

OS

Windows

Ubuntu (LINUX)

RedHat (RHEL)

IDE

Microsoft Visual Studio

Eclipse

UML

Doxygen

Doxygraph

GraphViz

Visual Paradigm

Code Repository

SVN

Mercurial | Git

PM

Jira

Azure DevOps

Cloud

Azure

AWS) GCP

LANGUAGES

Icelandic: Native

English: Fluent

Danish: Basic

German: Basic

generators. A process that requires CAD geometry, meshing, and fluid dynamics simulation of its components. Oversaw and ran the local IT administration for Windows, Linux, and HPC clusters. The HPC cluster was an essential component of the Wind R&D operation as it provided computing resources for the Computational Fluid Dynamics simulations, blade optimization, structural analysis, and system dynamics. Responsible for 3D printing operations which included field testable turbine components as well as scalable models. Algorithm development of multiple tools written in C/C++, FORTRAN, CUDA, and OpenCL.

Service Engineer | Siemens Energy

March 2008 - January 2011

Orlando, FL

An energy entity of one of the largest conglomerates in the world. Engineering leader for generator projects that need complete rewind, generators from one of the largest nuclear power plants in the world. Analyzed, engineered solutions, and made recommendations for any engineering-related changes or problems. Developed new methods and equipment that could reduce rewinding efforts by up to days. Supported fields engineers by recommending a resolution to their problems and product change management (PCMs). Performed generator vibration analysis that can prevent catastrophic failures to the generator. Led multiple research and development projects related to servicing turbine generators. Developed and wrote manuals for the engineering team. Performed readiness reviews and consulted power plant owners or operators.

PATENTS

Predictive test for melanoma patient benefit from pd-1 antibody drug and classifier development methods | Biodesix WO2017011439A1

2017 - 01 - 19

Steamboat Springs, CO

Predictive test for melanoma patient benefit from antibody drug blocking lig- and activation of the T-cell programmed cell death 1 (PD-1) checkpoint pro- tein and classifier development methods | Biodesix US20170039345A1

2016 - 07 - 12

Steamboat Springs, CO

Bagged Filtering Method for Selection and Deselection of Features for Classi- fication | Biodesix US20160321561A1

2016 - 04 - 05

Steamboat Springs, CO

Trailing edge modifications for wind turbine airfoil | Siemens EP2921697A1

2015 - 03 - 20

Boulder, CO

Vortex generators aligned with trailing edge features on wind turbine blade | Siemens US9476406B2

2014 - 04 - 14

Boulder, CO

Rotor blade of a wind turbine | Siemens US20150132141A1

2013 - 11 - 08

Boulder, CO

Reduced noise vortex generator for wind turbine blade, | Siemens US2015001040

2013 - 07 - 08 Boulder, CO Airfoil trailing edge apparatus for noise reduction | Siemens US20150050154A1 **2013 - 05 - 23** Boulder, CO Slat with tip vortex modification appendage for wind turbine | Siemens EP2647836A2 **2013 - 02 - 11** Boulder, CO **PUBLICATIONS & POSTERS** A classifier development platform optimized for precision medicine test discov- ery | J. Roder, et al. **2017** PLOS Computational Biology. A Pre-Treatment Mass Spectrometry-Based Serum Proteomic Test is Able to Stratify Patients with Ovarian Cancer Receiving Adjuvant Chemotherapy According to Overall and Disease-Free Survival and Identify Patients Likely to Exhibit Chemo-Resistance | S. Kasimir-Bauer, T. Krivak, T. Herzog, H. Roder et al. 2017 The Society of Gynecologic Oncology (SGO) A mass spectrometry-based serum test to predict outcome of treatment with nivolumab: Analysis of samples taken during therapy | J. Weber, H. Roder, et al. **2016** American Association for Cancer Research (AACR) A test identifying advanced melanoma patients with long survival outcomes on nivolumab shows potential for selection for benefit from combination check-point blockade | J. Weber, H. Kluger, R. Halaban, et al. **=** 2016 Society for Biological Therapy of Cancer (SITC) A mass spectrometry-based serum protein test for prognosis of patients with MDS | Roder J, Loffler-Ragg J, Stauder R, et al. 2015 American Association for Cancer Research (AACR) Creating molecular diagnostic tests with supervised learning using timeto- event data | H. Roder et al.

Pre-treatment patient selection for nivolumab benefit based on serum mass spectra | Weber J, Martinez AJ, Roder H, et al.

2015

2015

■ Journal for Immunother- apy of Cancer

Rocky Mountain Bioinformatics Conference

EDUCATION

M.Sc Computer Science Stanford University	
■ 2013 - • S	Stanford, CA
M.Sc Aerospace Engineer Embry-Ride	dle Aeronautical University
Minor in Computer Science Embry-Ri 2005 - 2008 sdf	iddle Aeronautical University Daytona Beach, FL
Minor in Mathematics Embry-Riddle 2005 - 2008 sdf	Aeronautical University Daytona Beach, FL
B.Sc in Aerospace Engineering Embry 2005 - 2008 sdf	 r-Riddle Aeronautical University ◆ Daytona Beach, FL